Tushar Mukherjee

E-Mail: in.tm.zero@gmail.com. DOB: 5th Day of June 1969.

Garia, Kolkata - 700084, West Bengal.

Mobile: +91 824 023 2048

BIO DATA

OBJECTIVE:

I am looking for an employment in an organization to get work satisfaction with full responsibilities for end to end delivery and admittance to learn & do more in an inspiring work sphere governed by encouraging principles.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY:

A self-motivated professional with Master Degree, from Calcutta University, having 20+ years of experience in **Operations & Administrations (System Integration & Service)**, with innate business sensibility & having expertise in Technology Solutions & Implementation, Resources Management and Support Services of IT Systems, LAN & Electrical Infrastructure & Training.

COMPETENCY AREAS:

- Planning
- Costing
- Operations
- Administration
- Process Development
- Quality Control
- Monitoring

- Training
- Service Delivery
- Vendor Management
- Procurement
- Reporting
- Client Relationship
- Documentation

KEY ACTIVITIES:

Planning

- Plans & activities to meet deliverables
- Resource allocation
- Budgeting and Financial plan
- Define quality expectations and targets
- Risks planning & contingency action plan
- Supplier identification and procurement planning
- Supplier QC planning

Execution

- Implement project plans to meet deliverables
- Monitor and control deliverables
- Control quality as per target
- Procurement tracking and monitoring
- Submission of project status reports
- Support and Direct Project team
- Evaluation of project performance

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

MAR 22.2021 - MAY 2022

GM – OPERATIONS & ADMINISTRATION – Ultimate Digital Solutions Pvt.Ltd.

Jharnet 2.0 network backbone, NOC, video conferencing, other services and user-level support covering entire Jharkhand under the OEM L&T.

JUL 01.2020 - MAR 21.2021

CONSULTANT – OPERATIONS & ADMINISTRATION - IT SYSTEM INTEGRATION – HP CBEC Project OPERATIONS & ADMINISTRATION - IT SYSTEM INTEGRATION PROJECTS & SERVICES

APR 01.2019 - JUN 30.2020

PC - OPERATIONS - IT SYSTEM INTEGRATION, TECH ELECON PVT.LTD. – A SUBSIDIARY OF ELECON ENGINEERING

Operations & Organizational Development - IT System Integration Projects (CBEC Saksham & Others) on behalf of Hewlett Packard India, Wipro (UBI RRB Upgradation) etc.

DEC 2017 - MAR 31.2019

CONSULTANT – OPERATIONS - IT SYSTEM INTEGRATION, AT AMIT NETWORK PVT.LTD. FOR CLIENT: TECH ELECON PVT.LTD.

Operations - IT System Integration Projects (<u>CBEC -Project Saksham & Others</u>) on behalf of Hewlett Packard India.

 Developed Automatic Acceptance Testing Report Generation to meet timeline. This had made a radical Easy and Error free Data Processing & Management, very crucial for the Project of this Scale.

SEP 2016 - NOV 2017

CONSULTANT, DIGITAL CARE PVT.LTD.

Operations, Administration & Support – IT System Integration Projects, Server & Network Support Services, in East & North-East India for Hewlett Packard.

NOV 24.2015 - SEP 16.2016

REGIONAL MANAGER – NORTH, RV SOLUTIONS PVT.LTD.

PAN India Operations - Service Delivery, IT System Integration Projects & Services in India.

OCT 1.2013 – NOV 20.2015 CONSULTANT, SELF EMPLOYED

Planning, Execution & Management Consultancy Services to Small Scale Segments about IT System Integration Projects, Computer Service Centre Management & Operations.

FEB 7.2013 - SEP 30.2013

REGIONAL MANAGER – EAST, NETOCOL SYSTEMS AND SOLUTIONS PVT.LTD.

Operations & BD - IT System Integration Projects in East & North-East India.

SEP 2011 – FEB 2.2013

REGIONAL MANAGER – EAST, DSM INFOCOM PVT.LTD.

Operations - Service Delivery, IT System Integration Projects in East & North-East India.

AUG 1999 - SEP 2011

BM > SRM > COO, DIGITAL CARE PVT.LTD.

Operations, Administration & Support - Service Delivery, IT System Integration Projects in East & North-East India.

NOV 1996 - JUL 1999

PRODUCTION MANAGER, BALARAM FOOD PRODUCTS

Production Control, Operations & Administration – of a Food Product Company in North 24 Parganas.

Developed Semi-Automatic innovative "Pick & Place" Cookie Processing Machine.

JUN 1995 - OCT 1996

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR, FOTOLAB.

Computer System Management & Operations of 180 Nos Systems, High End Laser Printer and 450 Nos Data Entry Operator for the Voter ID Card Project of East & North-East India.

■ Implemented "i-Link & i-Serve Data Communication between Computers". This had made a revolutionary Easy and Error free

JAN 1994 – JUN 1995

CUSTOMER SUPPORT EXECUTIVE, COMPUCARE.

Training and Technical Support - to the DTP Houses for DTP Systems and associated Software in West Bengal.

ACHIEVEMENT & EXPERIENCE:

IT SYSTEM INTEGRATION PROJECTS:

Comprising of Installation, Configuration & Commissioning of Computer / Network / Cloud / CCTV / Fire Alarm / L & E Infrastructure / Leased Line / Campus Networking with Wi-Fi / Optical Fibre Networking including Trenching by HDD.

- Executed Phase 2 of Central Board of Excise and Customs "Computerization Network, LT Electrical & Computer Implementation" CBEC Project Saksham in West Bengal, Sikkim, Bihar, Jharkhand, Orissa & Assam
- Phase 1 of Central Board of Excise and Customs "Computerization Network & LT Electrical Project in West Bengal, Sikkim, Bihar, Jharkhand, Orissa & Assam
- Crime & Criminal Tracking Network System Network, LT Electrical & Computer Implementation Project in West Bengal
- Campus Networking, LT Electrical & Computer Implementation at LCS Raxaul
- Campus Networking, LT Electrical & Computer Implementation at ICP Petrapole
- Wi-Fi Campus Networking at Guru Nanak College, West Bengal
- Mission Mode e-Court Computerization & Networking Project for National Informatics Centre in Jharkhand
- Network & Computerization Project of West Bengal State Electricity Board with Unix & Oracle Installation
- Network & Computerization Project of National Insurance
- Network & Computerization Project of Allahabad Bank with SCO Unix & Virtual Disk Mirroring
- Network & Computerization Project of Department of Income Tax, BSNL, LICI
- Metropolitan Area Network Project of Life Insurance Corporation of India

VSAT SYSTEM INTEGRATION PROJECTS:

Comprising of Installation, Configuration, Commissioning & Management of V-SAT Systems.

- V-SAT Network Project in Sikkim for National Informatics Centre
- V-SAT Network Project of Sahara India in Bihar, UP & Assam
- V-SAT Network Project of Playwin More than 2500 Retail V-SAT Centre West Bengal, Sikkim

DATA CENTRE INTEGRATION PROJECTS:

Comprising of Installation, Configuration, Commissioning of Computers, BMS, Civil & Interior Works

- Mini Data Centre Project of Life Insurance Corporation of India in South & West India.
- Operation Management of SAIL DC & DR in Kolkata & Chennai.

OS & APPLICATION SOFTWARE RELATED PROJECTS:

Comprising of Software Installation, Configuration of Computers, Printers, and Networks Etc.

Implementation of CBS of UBI, CBOP, BOI, UCO etc

TRAINING PROJECTS:

Comprising of Training of Various Application Software Modules.

- Food Corporation of India Depot Online System Training Project in Depots spreading all over India
- ERNET School Training Project, spreading most part of India

COMPUTER SKILLS:

CP/M, DOS, Mac System 7, Unix (BSD & SCO), MS Windows, 8051 Assembly Language, MS Office Suite, MS Visio.

EQUIPMENT SKILLS:

V-SAT + Server + PC + 8051 Development System (Assembly & Maintenance Level with OS); Router – Entry Configuration Level; Programmable Timer, Logic Tester, Spectrum Analyzer, Oscilloscope – Entry Level, DMM, Cable Analyzer, Optical Time Domain Reflectometer – Expert Operator Level.

ACADEMICS:

 M.Sc. (Anthropology) having 56.04% and Specialized in Demography having 90.00% marks from Calcutta University - Ballygunge Science & Technology College Campus in the year 1994.

TRAININGS:

- "Basic Electronics, MCU Application & Programming", from Bharat Electronics, Habra, North 24 Parganas.
- "Advance Desk Top Publishing" from Brainware Computer Academy, Calcutta.
- "Applications of Computer & Industrial Uses" from Modular Systems, Pune. Sponsored By M/S.
 Computere.
- "Prolient Service Engineer" from Hewlett & Packard, Bangalore. Sponsored By M/S. Digital Care (P)
 Limited.
- "Micro-eMBA (SM) Program" Online Free Management Library.
- Earned 35 PDU for PMP Certification from QValue Services Kolkata.
- Doing edX Micro Master Programme in Operations Management and related Online Self-Paced Course

R & D INTERESTS:

- Long Range Integrated Radio
- Embedded Electronics & MEMS

Last Remuneration: INR. 6,01,200 + Perks & Other financial benefits.

NATIONALITY: Indian
RELIGION: Hinduism
GENDER: Male

FATHER'S NAME: Sri Siddheswar Mukherjee

Date: 19 Sep 2023 Signature:

Place: Kolkata Tushar Mukherjee